Guide to the Barney Rosset papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Chronological Materials, 1879-2005
  - 1998
    - May -December 1998 Correspondence, Articles, and Interviews (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - 1999
    - "Strange Victory" in Ireland (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - January -December Correspondence, Articles, Interviews (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - 2000
    - Assorted Articles, Correspondence, and Interviews (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - 2001
    - Assorted Articles, Correspondence, and Interviews (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - 2002
    - Assorted Articles, Correspondence, and Interviews (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - 2003
    - Assorted Articles, Correspondence, and Interviews (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - 2004
    - Assorted Articles, Correspondence, and Interviews (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - 2005
    - Assorted Articles, Correspondence, and Interviews (Box 8, Folder 40)
- Series III: Photographs, 1895-2008
  The chronological arrangement of this series follows the order in which the original binders were serialized. The photographs, negatives, and printouts reproducing scanned images were transferred to folders but generally kept in the plastic sheets in which they came unless these had been damaged or were deemed unsuitable. Inserted among some of the photographs are correspondence, notes, and print matter. The photographs range from personal, family souvenirs to events related to Rosset's professional life as publisher where many famous literati can be seen. The series notably includes photographs Rosset took in China during World War II. As a result of the original arrangement and its labels given by Rosset, some of the folder titles are identical, but their contents are not necessarily duplicates.
  - Scanned Photos Chronologically
    - 1895-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 41-42)
      - Computer File Note (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - 1953 to Present, 1953-2003 (Box 8, Folder 44-45)
  - Barney Rosset Family Photos 1920s/1930s 1920-1939, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
  - Chronological to 1940 1890 to 1940, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 5-9)
  - 1940 Francis Parker Yearbook
    - Originals, Scans, and Assorted Articles, 1937-1941 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Scanned, 1937-1941 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1940s Various Photos
    - 1942 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - 1943 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - 1944 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - 1946 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - 1947 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - 1948 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Early Army: Pre-China, 1945 and Charlevoix, Michigan, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - China, 1944-1996
    - China People 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Luichow 1945, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 20-21)
    - Kiangkoa Battle, April 1945 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Kunming Medical (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Kweiyang, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - OSS Kweiyang, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - China and India, 1945-1946, (3 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 26-28)
    - Kiangkoa, Kweilin, Liuchow, and Shanghai, 1944-1945, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 29-30)
    - Shanghai (Return to New York City, 1945) (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - China and Roosevelt Funeral, April 1945 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Japanese Surrender at Nanking and Celebrations, 1945, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 33-34)
    - Miscellaneous Photos & Laser Prints, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - WWII Negatives, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 36-37)
    - Kunming, 1989-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 38-39)
    - "China in Conflict" at Janos Gat Gallery, February-March2002 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - 1950s
    - Grove, Hamptons, Brooklyn
      - "1950s À" (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - 1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - East Hampton and Miscellaneous Slides, (3 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 4-6)
    - Barney Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Scanned Photos
      - 1952 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - 1953 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - 1954 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - 1955 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - 1958 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - 1959 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Flandre, August 23rd, 1953 Wedding Day (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - 1953 Rosenberg House Hamptons (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Quonset House and East Hamptons, 1954-2007 (Box 10, Folder 16-18)
    - Scanned Slides and Negatives, 1941-1963 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Evergreen Theatre, Linc Bonnel, and Peter Rosset, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Corso, Ginsberg, Rosset, New York City 1957 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Beckett End Game, Paris 1957 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Peter Rosset, 1955-1968, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
    - Peter Rosset and Others, 1953-1960 and Later, 1953-1971, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 25-26)
    - Peter Rosset by Hella Hamid (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - 1960s
    - Various Photos, Barney, Christine, Beckett, Others
      - 1960s À (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - 1960 (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - 1961 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - 1962 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - 1963 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - 1965 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - 1968 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      - 1964 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - 1960 Maurice (Girodias), (Marguerite) Duras,, (Kenzaburo) Oe, Haskell (Wexler), etc. (with matchbooks) (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - "Christmas in Chicago," 1965 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "East Hampton, Etc.," 1968-1978 (with negatives) (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "East Hampton," 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "East Hampton/Quonset and Ranch…" 1969 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Family and Dogs, 1965-1969 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "East Hampton," 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - 1970s
    - "Grove Office Photos 11th St.," 1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Chicago--Mary Rosset," 1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Norman Mailer party Houston St (Lennon, Ono)," 1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "EH," 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Rosset Family Jamaica," ca 1970s (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Peter Rosset Grad. Brown Univ.," 1977 1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Peter, Christina, Barney--India, Benares, Nepal," 1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Sebastian and Sarah Uman. Beckett Rosset--Jamaica," 1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Jamaica," 1971 1976 1979 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Mitchell Photos--Vetheuil," 1979 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1980s
    - "Weidenfeld," 1980-1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "GOA, Lisa and Barney," 1980 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "East Hampton--Chantal, Lisa, Beckett, Tansey," 1980s (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - "Jamaica," 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "East Hampton," 1980s (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Photos East Hampton," 1980s (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "East Hampton, Hand's Creek--Chantal and Family, Friends," 1980s, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
    - "Chantal E.H. and N.Y.--Family," 1982-1983, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 19-20)
    - "East Hampton," 1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "American Booksellers Association show, S.F.," 1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Costa Rica," 1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Nicaragua and Costa Rica," 1987, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - "Paris--December," 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "East Hampton--Chantal, Beckett, Lisa, Kim, etc.," 1988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Jamaica--Kim NY," 1988 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "Samuel Beckett--Rest Home," 1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "Costa Rica," 1988, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
    - "New York," 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "ABA Wash. D.C.--Boston," 1989 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "James Brooks Opening," October 1989 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "East Hampton, Family," 1989 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - "Reading--Stirrings Still," 1989 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Nicaragua"
      - "July," 1989 (Print Matter) (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - "July 18-20," 1989, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 18-19)
      - "July 21-22," 1989 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - "July 23-24," 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "Thailand--First Trip," 1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "East Hampton," 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - "Barney Photos, 1980s-1990s" 1950s-2006 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1990s
    - "Nicaragua Elections," 1990, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - "Thailand," 1990, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
    - "Thailand and Cambodia," 1990, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
    - "VAAN Bangkok," 1990 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - "Thailand Turn of the Century," 1990s (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - "Photos March-December," 1990, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
    - "Laos, Cambodia, Vietnam," August 1990 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - "East Hampton--Thanksgiving, Christmas, New Year's Eve," 1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Thailand, Pattaya," 1991 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Malaysia," 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Vilgot Sjoman--EH 990, NY 1992" 1990-1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "EH Summer," 1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "Hands Creek EH," 1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "East Hampton, Thai Dinner," 1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "D.C., New York, East Hampton," 1991 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "OE," 1991-1997 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "East Hampton, D.C.," 1992 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "Bodega Bay, San Fran," 1992 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "New York Photos," 1992 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "Thailand--India," 1993 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "India Trip," 1993 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Michael Ginzburg Book Party," 1993 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - "Haskel Wexler Photos," Undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - "San Fran Beat Streets," 1994 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "New York Photos," 1994 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "Eleutheria Reading--National Arts Club," 1994-1995, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - "Original Photos Scanned," 1990s-2004 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Beckett at Lincoln Center," 1988-1996 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "San Diego Beckett Society," 1995 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Terence Strick Graduation," 1994 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Peter & Mary Elena Wedding," 1994 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - "Mill Valley, May umi Oda," 1994 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "The Nobel Prize, Kensaburo Oe," 1994 (Print Matter) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - "Kenzaburo Oe, Nobel Prize, Stockholm," 1966 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - "Oe and Rosset Tokyo," 1996 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "New York," 1995, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
    - "East Hampton--Barney's Birthday," 1995 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - "Arkansas Family," 1995 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - "Vietnam, Cambodia, China," 1995, (3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 17-19)
    - "New York Photos," 1996 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "New York Photos," 1996 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Thailand, Oct/Nov," 1996 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "East Hampton NYC," 1997, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
    - "Barney 75th Birthday, Copy 2 & Negatives," 1997 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Mitchell Photos--Danziger Gallery," 1998 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Ever. Rev. Party (Milazzo-Bianco)," 1998 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - "Photos 1998"
      - "Feb to Aug," 1998 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - "Sep to Dec," 1998 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - "New York, Februaryto June," 1999, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
    - "New York, September to December," 1999 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "Ev. Rev. Rdr. Party, 10th St.," 1999 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Plimpton Plaing Ping Pong," circa 1999 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - "Bangkok--C. Moore, December," 1999 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - 2000s
    - "Chiapas-Mexico-New Year's Eve," 2000 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "Bangkok, Chiang Mai," 2000 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - "San Cristobal Mexico, Christmas New Year's," 2000-2001 2005, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 18-19)
    - "Photos, 2000 to June 2001" 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Photos 2001 to February2002" 2001-2002 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Thailand," 2002 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Dublin, Trinity College, Galway," 2003 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Peter, Chantal, and Barney Rosset--Chang Mai," 2003 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "East Hampton," 2003 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "New York Blackout," 2003 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Photos 2002 Early 2003" 2002-2003, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - "Beat Conference UNC," 2004 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Photos May 2004 to Dec 2005" 2004-2005 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "Casey Kelbaugh Photos NY Times," 2006 (printouts) (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Print Matter "2007" 2007 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "Wedding Photos, Astrid & Barney," 2007 (with CD) (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - "Misc," 2006-2007 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "San Cristobal," 2008 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Subject Files, 1841-2011
  The largest of the collection, this series contains drafts, correspondence, clippings, photographs, and notes gathered by Rosset over the years, reflecting his interests, tastes, concerns, both professional and personal. Included here are Rosset's FOIA files, the notes and drafts of his Autobiography, The Subject is Left-Handed, materials related to his 1948 documentary Strange Victory, correspondence with friends, lovers, colleagues, publishers, authors and artists, his travel documents, including original print matter Rosset collected, his passports, licenses, etc., as well as materials about/from Grove Press, Evergreen Review, Grove Film, and a trove of interviews and press about Rosset. The dates correspond largely to the notations made on the original binders, even when the documents have been transcribed and printed at a later date. Materials are often a combination of originals and transcriptions, or photocopies, or printouts, without originals.
  - "196 West Houston St.," 1968-1987 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "American Association for the United Nations," 1950 1969 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "American Family--Krug, Poilier, Rosset," 1962-1986 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "Army Record," 1944-1948, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    (includes leather sigil)
  - "A.S.U. Summer Camp," 1941 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Autobiography
    - General, 1986-2000s (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Assemblage Part III A, Grove Years," 1949-2000s, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - "Assemblage Part III B, Grove Years," 1967-2001, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
    - "Geller Interviews--Subject is Left Handed," 1951-2003, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
    - "Geller--Originals," 1987 Undated, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
    - "Gale Barsh and other sections," 1944-1948 Undated, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 16-17)
    - "Gontarski--The Subject is Left-Handed," ca 1990s, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 18-19)
    - "Gontarski--The Subject is Left-Handed," Undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "Grove Genesis," 1949-1951 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - "Grove History (compiled from Bryant notes)," 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "The Lukas Prize Project," 2002-2004 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "J. Anthony Lukas, Work-in-Progress Award Proposal," 2003 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Materials--Volume 2," 1951-1983 Undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Outlines," 2007 Undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "Part One," 2006-2007, (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
    - "Part Two," 2007-2008, (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
    - "William Bryant Autobio MSS," 2004 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "Gale Barsh," 1939-1948 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "Eric Bentley," 1978-1986 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - "Robert Bernstein," 1985-1988 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - "Blue Moon Covers," 1988 Undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - "Book Business--J. Epstein," Undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - "Georges Borchardt," 1972-2000, (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 16-17)
  - "Steve Brower--Stories," 2007 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - William Burroughs
    - General, 1960-1997 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - "Articles," 1962-1994 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - "Contracts, Articles, Essays," 1960-1997, (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 21-22)
    - "Correspondence Originals," 1960-1965, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - "Correspondence Originals," 1966-1993 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Correspondence Third Copy," 1960-1993, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
    - "Work in Progress Articles," 1960-1980 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "By Heart--Spoon Jackson and Judith Tennenbaum," 2009 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - "John Calder," 1974-1986 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - "John Calder--Excerpts from PURSUIT," 1985 2001 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - "China Letters"
    - "Articles, Letters," 1943-1945 2007 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "Originals," 1944 2006, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
    - "Originals, Jan-June," 1945 2004, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 13-14)
    - "Originals, July -December," 1945 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "Pre-China Letters," Undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - "Jacqueline Duheme"
    - "Letters--Master," 1960-1961 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - "Letters--Originals," 1960-1961 1999 (1 of 3 folders) (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - "Letters--Originals," 1960-1961 1999 (2 of 3 folders) (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Evergreen Review
    - "Black Studies at Grove and Evergreen," Undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Richard Ellis Dissertation
      - "Dissertation on Evergreen, Part I," 1977 2009 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - 'Thesis, Part II," 1977 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - "Thesis Part III," 1977 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "Foxrock," 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Printouts
      - "100," 1998 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - "101," 1998 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - "122," March2010 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - "Volume 1, Number 2," 1957 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - "Volume 1, Number 3," 1957 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - "Volume 1, Number 4," 1957 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - "Volume 6, Number 23," 1962 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Alain Robbe-Grillet," 1957-2009 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "Jerry Tallmer," 1959-1966 2007 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - "Francine Felsenthal," 1959-1985 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - "Wallace Fowlie," 1951-1991 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - "Fowlie," 195-1991 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - "Fowlie--Italy Experience--Rimbaud Course, New School," 1951 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)
    - General
      - 1950 1959 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - 1960-1967 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - 1968-1969, (2 folders) (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
      - 1970 ("Quiet Days in Clichy Case") (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - 1974-1975, (2 folders) (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
      - 1975-1977, (2 folders) (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
      - 1978-1981 1987, (2 folders) (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
    - "Army," 1943-1945 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - "Army Intelligence," 1943-1948 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - "Cummings Memorandum," 2000 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - "Documents," 1943-1945 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - "Documents and Forms," 1943-1945 1975 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "Grove Press against CIA," 1978-1980 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - "Lowenstein Book," 1984-1987 (with audio tapes), (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 18-20)
    - "Miscellaneous Intelligence Information," 1940s-1970 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - "Originals"
      - 1940s (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - 1961-1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - 1967-1972 2007, (2 folders) (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
    - "Secondary Papers"
      - 1937 1944-1975, (3 folders) (Box 23, Folder 6-8)
      - 1975-1981, (2 folders) (Box 23, Folder 9-10)
  - "Jean Genet," 1960-1974 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Maurice Girodias
    - "Articles," 1956-1994 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - "Auto-Bio FRENCH," 1960-1967, (2 folders) (Box 23, Folder 13-14)
    - "Auto-Bio, Pages 368-537," Undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - "Casement Originals," 1957-1959 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - "Casement Originals," 1957-1959 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "Correspondence," 1966-1986 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "Correspondence Disk 71c," 1965-1969 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "Correspondence, Olympia Reader," 1966-1981 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "Correspondence Originals," 1953-1973, (3 folders) (Box 24, Folder 5-7)
    - "Master Copy," 1953-1969, (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 8-9)
    - "Master Copy," 1959 1970-1986 2009 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - "Me and Maurice," 2005-2007 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - "Naked Lunch," 1959-1969, (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
    - "Olympia Press," 1965, (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 14-15)
    - "Olympia Reader, Originals," 1964, (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 16-17)
    - "Originals--Not on Disk," 1953-2004 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - "Herbert Gold," 1981-2007 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - "Gontarski, U. of N.C.," 1998 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "Grove Leftovers," 1972-1989 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - "Gruen-The Party's Over Now," Undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "Hampshire College/Adele Simmons/Millstein piece," 1951-2003 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - "Ann Holt"
    - General, 1959-1992 Undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - "Alverda Brown Muhammad," 1959-1992 Undated, (2 folders) (Box 7-8)
      (with Audio Tapes)
  - Irish Materials
    - "Irish Land League Crisis," 1940 2004, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
    - "Joe Clarke--Maamtrasna--Irish Liberation," 2004 Undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - "Rosset's Irish Citizenship and Family," 1990-2005 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - "Tansey Family--Ireland & USA," 1967-2004 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - "Tansey Trial Research," 1841-2004, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 14-15)
  - "Bettina Jonic-Writings, Correspondence," 1963-2000, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 16-17)
  - "Journal-1950--Original" 1940-1950 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - "Kay, Cicellis, Rosset Correspondence," 1955-2000, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 19-20)
  - Lady Chatterley
    - General, 1954-1958 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - "Covers," ca 1960s (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - "Geller, Rosset, Rembar," 1959 2000 Undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - "Lady C. by R. Caffrey," 1959 1985 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - "The Lady Shall Lead Us" and Others," Undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - "Joseph Liss--Originals," 1967-2003 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Literary Agents," 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Lo's Diary
    - "Articles, Reviews, Essays," 1998-2000, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 8-9)
    - "Correspondence," 1998-1999, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 10-11)
    - "Legal, Sales, Production," 1998-2000, (3 folders) (Box 26, Folder 12-14)
  - "Brian McCord"
    - General, 1996-2001 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - "Dissertation--Grove Press," 2002, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 16-17)
    - "Grove Press and Gay Identity--Dissertation," 2000-2002 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - "James McManus Fiction," 1986-2002 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Henry Miller
    - General, 1941-2007, (3 folders) (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    - "Articles," 1941-2005 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "Assorted Articles," 1962-2005, (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
    - "Chicago Trial," 1941-2003 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - "Correspondence Originals," 1959-1965, (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 8-9)
    - "Correspondence Originals," 1966-1991, (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 10-11)
    - "The Cosmological Eye," 1939 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - "Laughlin Article by Donald Hall," 1983 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - "Henry Miller in Lotus Land," 1952 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - "Henry Miller in Lotus Land and VALERIE letter," 1952 1960 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - "Letters," 1969-1976 (with letters from Alain Robbe-Grillet) (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - "Master Disk," 1959-2004, (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 17-18)
    - "Opus Pistorum Reference," 1984-2003 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - "Karl Orend," 1995-2004 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - "Minkoff, UNC, BC, NYU Sales/Correspondence," 1992-1995 (with negatives and photographs) (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Joan Mitchell
    - General, 1986-1998 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - "Articles," 1961-2007 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - "1950 and later," 1955-1986 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - "Correspondence-Photos," 1947-1986 Undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - "Letters (Revised)," 1955-1983 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - "Mitchell-Rosset"
        - 1947 (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - 1948 (Box 28, Folder 7)
        - "Final," 1948 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - "MSS II," 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - "Originals," 1952-1988 (with Decree of Divorce) (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - "Revised and Final," 1947-1948, (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 11-12)
      - "Rosset to Mitchell"
        - 1948-1979 (Box 28, Folder 13)
        - "Originals," 1948-1979 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - "Volumes I-III, Milazzo article," 1947-1986, (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 15-16)
    - "Early News Clippings and Catalogues," 1947-2006 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - "Mitchell Foundation-Riopelle Obit," 2002 (Box 28, Folder 18)